Um...
"Experiment Result: Human is dead,
mismatch."
Human is dead?
Yeah.
Someone...
...died?
I think so. Probably.
What does it say after that?
The details are in Jellyman's report #143.
Jellyman's Report?
What's that?
How should I know?
But there's a weird database on this server.
What's this?
Some kind of program code, I think.
I don't get it!
Daru?
This doesn't make any sense!
Die! Damn it!
We should stop.
This is the first time I've had an
"I was this close to getting it!" experience.
Good job.
Go ahead and take a break.
You don't have to tell me. I'm done.
Daru, I've got canned fishcake stew.
Thanks.
Program code...
The IBN 5100 was created before BASIC,
so it can read IBN's proprietary programming languages or something...
I need the IBN 5100's abilities to stop their plans.
I'd like to talk to you in detail.
This is my email address.
If you contact me, I'll answer.
John Titor
There's something I want to ask you
Even the billions of heartbeats in the world
suujuuoku mo no kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
are nothing to you but insignificant
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
Whether we’re trapped in the past or lamenting over the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
predetermination does not allow even the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
are but vain privileges allowed to us
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what both clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
So now I cross worldlines every second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no loop e to
And so, a time loop without sadness will once again
nomikomareteyuku kodoku no kansokusha
engulf me, the lone observer
Interpreter
Rendezvous
There are a lot here.
Both Daru and I've been working all night
and haven't been home.
And everything Daru wears,
from his T-shirts to his underwear, is XXXL.
It's Faris!
I spy Okabe Rintaro!
'Sup!
I should warn you.
One, my name is Hououin Kyouma.
Two, that greeting is dangero—
'Sup, Suzu!
You too?
Actually, when did you two meet?
We live in the same building.
Naturally, we'd at least know each other's face.
Suzu gave me this Rai-Net card.
It's gold!
Where are you going?
To go do the laundry.
Okarin and Daru have been up all night for days.
Part-timer!
If you don't do your job, I'll fire you.
Oh, no...
You too, Okabe.
Keep your hands off my part-timer.
Don't you think you're the one in love, Mr. Braun?
Say that when Nae's around. I dare you.
I'll seriously kill you.
Nae?
The little woodland creature?
Don't call my daughter a woodland creature!
How could I be in love with a little kid like her, anyway?
I'm not a kid.
I'm an adult and a warrior!
I like that look, Part-Time Warrior.
Always remember that look.
If you do,
someday, you'll be able to change classes to a true warrior—
You, shut up.
When you talk, it—
I'm already a warrior!
Why do I get all the weirdos?
Bye.
We, too...
That's a habit of Mayuri's.
I've taken to calling it the "Stardust Handshake."
I was wondering if I could reach the stars...
You can't even see the stars.
You know, even in the daytime, the stars are still there.
Those were powerful EM waves.
A cellular malfunction's a real possibility.
But I saw that banana.
The PhoneWave (name subject to change) is a time machine!
The hell it is.
Faris...
Why'd this happen to you?
I'm closing the lid.
Daru is like the universe—constantly expanding.
Shining Finger?
What's Titor doing?
He told me to message him.
Tell me how to reach the Super Haker!
Moeka
"Tell me how to reach—"
Enough already!
You have a new message
John Titor
Are you for real?
Thank you for the message.
Regarding the image you sent of that program,
it is indeed a proprietary programming language developed by IBN,
and decoding it will require an IBN 5100.
Listen to me!
The Future Gadget Laboratory
will now initiate an emergency secret plan!
Okarin, what's wrong?
Wake up, Daru!
We're about to engage in battle with
an immense organization that controls the world from the shadows!
It's SERN!
They're a worldwide organization
obsessed with dark science, and they're plotting a huge conspiracy!
The world only needs one mad scientist!
We must complete our quest before they do!
I don't understand what you're saying.
First, we need an IBN 5100.
Then, we'll decode SERN's mysterious program.
Get ready to leave!
But Mayushii has her part-time job today.
So I get to do it alone...
Name            :  Shining Finger
Subject     :  Sorry if I'm bothering you.
Are you mad? Sorry if I'm bothering you.
I really need the IBN 5100 information,
and right now, you're the only one I can ask...
It might be worth exchanging information.
Assistant?
Wait.
What?
Come with me.
Hey!
You destroyed the jacket's shoulder...
Let's both do our best
I don't have any real information.
How about you?
Moeka
"I don't have any real information."
Useless!
Why are you glaring at me?
Don't worry about it.
It's not your fault.
I'd rather you didn't blame me for your problems.
Are you sulking?
Mayuri was worried that you might've gotten upset.
You're too old to act like a little kid.
You're the last person I want to hear that from.
Anyway, what did you want to talk to me about?
It's simple.
Stop sulking, come back to the lab, and work, Christina.
I'd like you to at least stick to calling me one thing.
Listen to people when they're talking, "The Zombie"!
Which of us isn't listening?
How'd I get involved with this guy?
I want to punch myself for giving in to my curiosity back then.
Again?
Are those messages that annoying?
Yes, you wouldn't believe it...
Is she also an Organization agent?
What's the Organization?
The Organization is the Organization!
It's an international secret organization,
controlling the world from the shadows!
That's just a conspiracy theory, thank you very—
What's wrong?
N-Nothing.
Really, it's nothing.
Any more questions, and I'll hit you!
Blaming others for your problems?
Come with me.
After we recover the laundry, I'll give you your mission.
You really think I'd follow you...
Laundry?
So that's where it is.
There isn't one at the hotel?
No, it's a pretty nice hotel....
but it's not my style to send everything I wear to the cleaners.
You found it, thanks to me.
You should be gratef—
No change?!
Of course not.
You don't think something'll happen when it spins, do you?
The answer lies in the components we find most natural.
Who would expect that hooking a cell phone to a microwave
would make a time machine—
It's not a time machine!
That was some kind of mistake!
Time machines only exist in science fiction.
I'll have no part of it.
Why do you try so hard to deny what you saw?
I'm not...
Could it be some kind of past trauma?
Yes, it happened when she was five.
Christina was struck by lightning on the grassy plains of Arkansas...
No, I wasn't.
Then why?
I told you.
It's theoretically impossible.
Theories are nothing more than words.
Accept what you've seen.
I refuse.
Why are you being so stub-
I said I refuse!
I don't want...
to make the same mistake my father made!
I'm sorry.
I got emotional.
Don't worry.
I deliberately provoked you to see what you'd do—
Anyway, the PhoneWave isn't a time machine.
I understand.
I'm sorry I forced you to join the lab.
You don't have to come anymore.
But I'll tell you this...
No one else will ever have the title of Lab Mem 004.
That number will be yours forever.
What do you think you're doing?!
What are you doing?
That was a great parting speech!
And that's what bugs me.
You still have your laundry, right?
I'll leave.
Bye.
What?
I'm getting you back.
You should reflect on your thoughtless actions.
Right, right.
Bye.
Wait.
Don't grab me there!
Do you know anything about the IBN 5100?
IBN?
It's an old PC.
What are you going to use it for?
You want to know?
You do.
Geez...
Just a bit.
The IBN 5100 is connected to SERN's secrets.
SERN is researching time travel,
and to decode their secret program,
we need the IBN 5100's special functionality.
Well?
Surprised?
How stupid.
I'm sorry I listened.
You... You snorted!
Why, you...
I'll show you. Just you wait!
So just you wait! Christina!
There's no "-tina"...
SERN is researching time travel.
We need the IBN 5100's special functionality.
Geez... I told her because she said she wanted to know.
A PC?
Yeah. An old PC...
Like, it costs 5,100 yen or something?
5,100... Maybe...
Okarin!
Hey, hey! Mayushii heard something amazing.
No Cell Phones
No cell phones.
Faris said she's seen the PC you're looking for.
No Cell Phones
No cell phones!
H-Hey!
Geez...
That's not enough!
Faris NyanNyan! Faris NyanNyan!
Faris NyanNyan!
What's this?
Everyone!
It's yours truly! Nyan!
We're starting the Faris Cup daytime group!
All of you, do your best to beat Faris
and win a special NyanNyan Omelet Rice!
Faris NyanNyan! Faris NyanNyan!
What's this?
Okarin!
Mayuri...
What's going on here? Some kind of space-time distortion?
No, it's the Faris Cup.
Faris is going to play Rai-Net Access Battlers with everyone.
Kyouma!
Are you going to participate too?
Faris can play up to ten at a time.
So there's still...
I refuse!
More importantly, the IBN 5100!
Where is it?
Well...
I'll tell you if you play.
Don't be stupid!
The fate of the planet's power structure depends on this!
Some stupid game—
If you won't play, then I'm sorry, but you'll have to leave.
You're just a maid, and you're having your master leave?
The IBN 5100...
I'm not listening!
There's no time.
I'm sorry, but I'll have to go all out.
You're really confident.
Okarin, can you win?
Faris is one of the country's best players.
Can I win?
You should be asking Faris that.
I have a plan that's never failed.
A plan?
Plan Code:
G-B-A-C-K.
I call it G-Back!
That sounds pretty amazing!
This'll be fun.
You say that now,
but when this plan explodes, you might not survive.
You're serious, aren't you, Kyouma?
Let's make this clear:
If I participate, you'll tell me everything.
Understood?
The cat ears never lie.
I'll teach you...
...that there are some opponents you just can't beat!
I lost!
So fast!
Mayushii's disappointed.
What was your plan?
Who knows?
But his constant charging and self-destructing basically screamed, "Get back."
G-back?
G-Back... Get Back?
That was a horrible joke, thank you very much.
However!
What?
Tell me what you know, Faris.
He recovers quickly.
You're arrogant for a loser.
I said if I participated, you'd tell me what you know.
In other words, I never cared about winning.
Is that right?
I don't really remember...
Remember it!
It was my brilliant plan!
Brilliant or cheating, one of the two.
Shut up!
Where's the IBN 5100?
I don't know...
You don't know?
I'm sure when I was little, Dad had one, but it's gone now.
Why, you...
Is that the secret move
you mastered in the Guiana Highlands, the Question-Dodge?
How'd you know?
Way to go, Kyouma.
You saw through my Cold Shoulder.
Is that really it?
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure the last time I saw it was at an Akihabara shrine.
Shrine?
"Kurisu,
thank you for messaging us all the way from Japan."
"I asked the professor about your question,
and he said that, yes, the IBN 5100
can analyze certain special programming languages."
He was serious?
A computer?
I'll have to ask my father.
An IBN 5100.
If he doesn't know what that is, tell him it's an old computer.
All right.
I'll ask him.
I'm counting on you.
End with the code words.
E-El... Psy Kongri...
It's Kongroo!
Hello?
It's Makise.
Makise?
Sorry, I don't remember a Makise.
Where'd we meet?
Paris? London?
Akihabara.
I just saw you!
What? It's my assistant?
Just say "Christina"!
There's no "-tina"!
You're as loud and bossy as ever.
Whose fault is that? Whose?
What do you want?
Where are you now?
Why do you care?
No reason.
I'm heading to Yanabayashi Shrine...
What was that?
Harassment?
Was that harassment?
What was that call about?
I just asked where you were.
No one called you.
No one called me.
I'm back!
Did you ask him?
Yes, he said that we have that PC here.
Really?
PC?
Do you mean an IBN 5100?
Yes.
Um, who's this?
My assistant.
Anyway, the IBN—
Wait!
What kind of introduction was that?
And I'm not your assistant!
I'm not here to introduce you.
It wouldn't even take ten seconds.
You're a pain, you know that?
Makise Kurisu, my assistant.
Right, right.
Fine, I'm your assistant.
So who are you?
U-Urushibara Luka.
How old are you?
Seventeen this year.
One year younger than me.
Really?
You look like a grownup, Makise.
You're pretty.
No... Not nearly as pretty as you.
Um... I'll call my dad.
It's better not to know some things, huh?
What do you mean?
I never thought it would happen.
Wh-What do you mean?
Um, well, the person who donated this told us...
that someday, a young man who needed it would appear,
so take good care of it.
It was ten years ago, I think?
So that's it...
It's fate.
The choice of Steins Gate!
That again?
IBN 5100 Portable Computer.
This is it.
Is that right?
Um, could we borrow it?
Certainly.
Thank you.
We're carrying this back! Help me!
But I refuse.
You're my assistant, Christina!
I'm not your assistant, and there's no "-tina"!
I'll get a cart.
We couldn't ask you for that, after you lent this to us.
Hey, assistant!
Show some respect for others!
Show some respect?
You really just said that?
You guys are good friends, huh?
Be nice to Luka too.
Yes, please.
Wait just a moment.
You have a nice father.
You think so?
I don't want to make the same mistake my father made!
What?
Nothing.
I'm sorry!
The cart's broken.
Why do I have to do this with you?
Shut up and carry it.
We've got a long way to go.
Hey...
What?
It's nothing!
What's with your provocations?
Wait!
If you carry it like that, I'll have to walk backward!
Start walking, assistant!
I can't...
I can't do this walking backward!
You can do it, assistant!
Thanks for the words of support, but no!
I suggest we walk sideways!
Actually, we need to!
I'm going to trip!
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
With my field of view restricted
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
I cannot escape the merciless control of the twelve
ansoku no asu wo negatta
While wishing for a tomorrow of repose
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
I headed for the sacred event horizon in my hand
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
Pledges are imprisoned, and false evidences are showing their outline
seimei no tenchi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
This world of life blindly lets the time pass by
habatake butterfly
Spread your wings
kiseki no butterfly
butterfly of miracles
anata he sasagu
I dedicate it to you
namida no butterfly
Oh butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
butterfly of radiance
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
everything will now be rewritten